hi I'm Nick Ortiz I'm a board certified
disability insurance attorney today I'm
here to talk to you about sudden life
insurance company and the top reasons
why Sun Life denies long term disability
claims just for reference these are not
presented in any particular order number
one insufficient medical records in
other words the insurance company
requested medical records from your
doctor or other medical provider and the
doctor's office never provided the
records number two
insufficient objective medical evidence
the insurance company may have medical
records but they don't believe that the
records are sufficient to show a
disabling condition some of the types of
objective records they're looking for
our x-rays MRIs CT scans and the like
number three the medical condition is
non verifiable or based primarily on
self-reported symptoms number four your
doctors didn't return forms or
questionnaires also known as attending
physician statements number five the
peer review physician does not agree
with your doctors in other words the
insurance company has hired a doctor to
review your records and their doctor
says that your conditions are less
limiting than your doctors say number
six the insurance company may say that
you're exaggerating your symptoms
qualify for disability number seven the
insurance company may have hired a
private investigator to conduct video
surveillance and the video footage is
inconsistent with your purported
limitations number eight your social
media profile the insurance company is
likely tracking you on Twitter Facebook
Linkedin and the like and they're gonna
argue that your postings are
inconsistent with your disabilities
number nine missed deadlines for example
you didn't file your initial application
for benefits in time or be your proof of
loss in time or see you didn't file your
appeal in time
number ten there may be a pre-existing
condition exclusion number eleven there
may be a specifically excluded condition
listed in the policy that says you
cannot qualify for benefits with that
condition number twelve you do not meet
or satisfy the definition of disability
under your specific plan or policy
number thirteen there's been a change in
the definition of the term disability
for example from own occupation
to any occupation after six twelve or
twenty four months before teen you may
be partially disabled but not totally
disabled under the policy number fifteen
you are out of work due to your own
choice but not due to your medical
condition and finally ERISA most group
plans not all but most are subject to
ERISA and that law very heavily favors
the insurance companies if you've been
denied benefits for one or a combination
of these reasons then we encourage you
to give us a call at eight five zero
three zero eight seven eight three three
our office has experience in dealing
with all these reasons why insurance
companies deny claims also if you'd like
more information I encourage you to
download a free copy of a book that I
wrote called the top ten mistakes that
will destroy your long-term disability
claim you can claim a free copy at WWE
Ltd be calm thank you for listening
[Music]